hi everyone.
I am Venkata Vedabathi Parthi.
I have been working in IT industry for
almost 12 years now, mainly around cloud
architecture, security, automation,
and modern application platforms.
So today I work as a lead cloud
solution architect, where I design
and help implementing multi-cloud
solutions for our enterprise.
So, and today I want to talk
about a problem, I think a lot
of us have seen in DevSecOps.
and, that is majorly how our pipelines
get access to the cloud resources, right?
So as you see the title, of the talk,
basically it is secretless multi-cloud
authentication with workload identity
for DevSecOps pipelines, right?
For DevSec, dev security
operations pipelines.
So the idea is pretty
straightforward here.
the instead of giving our pipelines
like long-lived cloud credentials, can
we let the workload prove who it is and
then give it a temporary access, right?
That's the primary idea So that's
what I'll talk through today.
the architecture, the security
model, the DevSecOps patterns, and
the AWS proof behind the approach.
Right?
not only AWS, but it
can be anything, right?
AWS, GCP or Azure, right?
You can implement it for
any, any cloud platform.
I just named the major cloud platform,
but it can be any cloud platform.
And, I'll also s-show one simple way
to quantify what changes when we move
from a credentials, that lives for
a year, to a federated session that
lives for minutes, literally minutes
or seconds too in a given scope.
Having said that, let's, move to
the original problem solution.
Original problem actually.
The problem actually.
So, let's start with this problem, right?
let's say when a CI/CD pipeline, needs
access to our AWS, Azure, to Google Cloud,
the traditional answer is like pretty
much, "Hey," everyone thinks like, "Hey,
I want to store these credentials in some
kind of, secret location or a secret key,
or store it in the on-prem EC2 servers,
receive it from there, and do store it in
the parameter store or secrets manager,"
wherever you want to store it, right?
So that's the traditional approach.
and on paper, it seems and
technically sounds manageable, right?
I'm like, "Hey, what's the--
just the credentials, right?
I go there and I just change it."
but think about, think about in the lines
of, like, your pipelines get multiplied
or your environment grows, right?
So handling one cloud environment,
handling one cloud environment to
multiple cloud environments, and think
about each multiple cloud environments
have multiple pipelines, DS pipelines,
data engineering pipelines, and any,
app, app pipelines or traditional, RPG
pipelines or whatever pipelines, right?
So think about they
keep on growing, right?
So it doesn't stay like that, right?
As, enterprise scale, your pipeline
should also scale, and especially with
this agentic culture and agentic MLOps.
So there is no, rest for the
pipelines or runners, right?
So that is the place.
and, that is a, that is a primary place
where we store the credentials, right?
So having said that Think
about it this way, right?
If you're managing multiple environments,
that credential can be end upped in
different, that credentials can be
end upped and referenced by multiple
repositories, runners, containers,
deployment jobs, whatever it is, right?
In different environments.
Eventually, we also need to deal with
one major problem, that is, rotation,
expiration, and making sure that we
don't lose the old credentials, right?
So if you lose the old, like if the--
let's say if you create an AWS secret
key and access key, and it is left alone,
and you've suddenly forgot the secret
key and you created a new, just to make
sure that IAM user is live, you want to
create, since you don't know where it is
referenced by wherever pipelines, right?
So you want to create, a new access
key with the same username, right?
So it makes, the pipeline continuous.
So, there are scenarios where many
we walk, we get into, but, the,
we all face that issues, right?
So that technically what I
understand and what it creates
is a rotation depth, right?
And, that's the-- and there is an
important issue and as, as well, like
think about just storing, credentials,
long-lived credentials, and it
has been exposed to, some party or
some-someone who doesn't need access.
We th-think about it being exposed
or some, let's say your contractors
or where- whoever it is, right?
It's been exposed for a certain period
of time and boom, and it's gone, right?
And you forget about it, and
somebody might, threat actors might
be used as, them on that, right?
So we should be very careful on that.
So instead of, what, what we
are talking here is like, it
can be credential sprawl, right?
So instead of asking us like, where do
we securely store the credentials, the
most important question we need to ask
is like, do we need to give workload a
permanent credentials in the first place?
That's the first question we need to ask.
That question leads us
to our workload identity.
So I would like to talk about
the core identity problem here.
So what is the Identity
over credentials, right?
Why do we need identity over credentials?
this is really the core idea
behind the whole approach, identity
over the credentials, right?
Rather than giving the workload a key
that is to carry around, we let the
workload prove who it is when it runs.
The flow is actually pretty simple.
The workload start, so the workload runs.
The workload start, it gets
a short-lived OIDC token that
represents, that workload, right?
So that represents that workload,
and behind the scenes, the target
cloud validates that token and
checks the claims we care about.
Technically, what in the step
two and step three, right?
So, and if everything matches our trust
policy, so you create a trust policy
and everything feels like it matches.
The trust policy usually in AWS,
in IAM, right, you store it in STS
and it's in the Azure role policy.
So that cloud issues the temporary
credentials with the permissions
that workload is allowed to have.
Like let's say I only want to
spin up a Lambda, and let's say I
want to only spin up an S3 bucket.
So the cloud technically creates
temporary credentials, which is
allowed to that policy itself.
Like, hey, you just need to
create an S3 bucket, you just
need to create an S3 bucket.
Nothing more than that, nor more
than that, or greater than that.
So there is an, there isn't a permanent
AWS key sitting in the pipeline,
but, the identity is established.
once the identity is established, when
the workload runs and the access expires,
when the temporary session is expired.
that's the shift I want to keep
in mind, as we go through this
rest of the presentation, right?
So we need to keep this in
mind, as we go through the,
presentation as I said, right?
So, now, we have established the identity.
Technically, why I think, OpenID,
Connect as a trust fabric, right?
So why OIDC?
In literally why OIDC, right?
OIDC, for the people who doesn't know,
but, OIDC gives us a standard way for one
system to make an identity, assertion.
Technically, it, it, it makes an trust,
to trust between-- It acts that, it
acts as, trust bridge between two
systems, technically to validate it.
Hey, what is it going on here
and what is going on here?
Do you believe this service?
Do you believe, this claim?
Hey, yes, we both match,
and I believe him.
That happens behind the
scenes in the OIDC framework.
it sorted out.
So in our case, I would
put it as this way, right?
Just for this talk.
the work- the workload platform, in
our case, the workload platform is
saying essentially like: Hey, this is
who I am, and, OIDC says this, right?
This is who I am, and this is the audience
I'm intended for, and these are the
claims, to describe what kind of context
I need to provide it to it, technically.
So the cloud provider can decide, in
our case, the cloud provider can decide
whether it trusts that issuer and whether
those claims satisfy the trust policy.
Of course, the federated token
and federated identity, that comes
into the picture in Azure role.
And that, that's important because,
we're no longer creating a secret
as a primary proof of identity.
So, because I don't want a secret, but
I want to trust it way before that.
Instead of, hey, whether to go
into the account and see a, get
a token or get a secret, right?
Instead of that, we are blocking them
in the first place and say that, "Hey,
prove your identity, then get into it."
get into, get a sec- go
into create a secret, right?
So that's the main logic we have, here.
So, we are establishing trust
between systems and then making
authorization decisions based
on the workload's identity.
And that becomes especially useful when
the workloads and the infrastructure
spreads across multiple cloud providers.
So I'm not talking about AWS
here, but think about like
one OIDC, it can talk to AWS.
One OIDC, it can,
specifically talk to, GCP.
One OIDC specifically
talk to Azure, right?
So, given, given the scope of LLMs
and everything, right, multi-cloud
culture is technically going way
far, what we understand, right?
Having said that, I'll
get into my architecture.
So, now let's put all together, right?
I talked about identity, I
talked about authorization.
I'll talk about authorization a bit
later, but I talked about identity
versus, hmm, credentials, right?
So why identity and
all of those, why OIDC.
So having seen this, slide, right, so I
can say that on the left, my architecture
usually talks about we have our workload.
It can be CI/CD pipelines, Kubernetes
workloads, ML jobs, whatever it is, right?
And, and other automation,
and other automation.
So the workload gets a
short-lived OIDC identity.
So as you say that, it's just
like a JSON web token, you get it.
And at the federation boundary,
we validate things like issuer.
Issuer, i- audience,
workload-specific claims.
So I, I'll talk a little bit broad
about this, in the next slides.
But, having said that, and keeping
this mind in the architecture here,
then we cross into the target cloud.
So taking these claims and taking
this identity, workload identity,
s- workload-specific claims.
So I, I point it as workload-specific
claims because it-- each cloud can
have its own workload-specific claims.
It can create its own
workload, specific claims.
So- in AWS that means like IAM and STS.
In GCP, technically we can use
Workload Identity Federation.
And in Azure, we can also use
Microsoft Entra Federation.
So think about OIDC can literally
connect all these three, right?
So the pattern is basically you
establish the identity, validate the
claims, and authorize the workload, and
then issue a temporary access, right?
So the, the GCP and Azure pieces are
literally, like, represent the, represent
the generalized multi-cloud pattern.
the-- like we are not proving anything
here, but we are saying like: Hey,
I established the connection, I
established the claims, and that claims
usually validate the tokens, and it
allows the secrets, and it allows
the, confidence to get into the, get
into the cloud environment altogether.
So think about in like multiple
pipelines running in multiple
environments, multiple clouds, they
need to validate the credentials, right?
So you don't need to store
credentials for each cloud, in your
pipelines, but you can literally
use the OIDC Federation identity.
You can create a temporary access
token for each of the pipeline behind
the scenes, and it can auto-automate
it and run the job for us, right?
That's the, flow which
we are talking about.
So having said that, I'll
jump into next, my model here.
what is about, what I want to talk
about the model and the calculation
here, like how can we achieve all nines?
how can we achieve all nines here, right?
So before considering the controls.
So now let's put that, let's put a number
here on one part of security model.
Imagine we have a credential that's
valid for three sixty-five days.
Now compare that with a federated
session that's valid for 15 minutes.
The calculation is simple, right?
one minus fifteen divided by the
number of minutes in a year, right?
That gives around ninety-nine
point nine nine percent reduction
in the credential validity window.
So now there's an important
clarification here.
I'm not saying that this means like
nine-- all nine to seven percent
reduction is probability of a breach.
But what I'm saying here is like,
that would be much stronger claim.
We-- And technically, I don't want
to sh-- evidence for that, right?
Because I have done it, but I want
to, as given the talk here, but
I want to show it like, what we
are, what we can achieve, right?
What we can say is that credentials
validity window is literally shorter
compared to the, long-lived tokens, right?
And that matters because the least
privilegization, no, sorry, because
the least privilege, claim validation,
monitoring, workload security I would like
think about all those combined, right?
with a short, shorter window, you have lot
of control compared to a long-lived token.
So this number is an exposure
of a window metric, not a breach
probability metric, right?
I cannot say it can be breached.
so there are some services which run
for years, but they're not breached yet.
But having said, I just want
to make sure that assumption
here clarity, clarified here.
so having said that, so now
let's little bit dive, into our
second chapter of things like,
DevSecOps in- integration, right?
So pipeline integ- pipeline integration
patterns and DevSecOps patterns.
So far, we talked about
the security model.
Now let's little bit bring
into DevSe- DevSecOps workflow,
like how the workflow works.
The goal isn't h- isn't it to
create another security process
that developers have to work around.
The goal here is to make the
secure path the normal path, right?
So that's the primary, and
that's the primitive objective
of this, my topic, right?
So I want-- The goal is to make the
secure path as the normal path at all.
normal, normal path technically.
Let's look, at what that means
in-- for CI/CD and MLOps, right?
yeah.
So in CI/CD Okay, this is
like pretty normal, basic.
the CI/CD process, the CI/CD flow, the
pipeline starts, and if you, if you see
the steps right, the pipeline starts,
the workflow establishes its identity.
The identity is exchanged for temporary
cloud access, and then the deployment
runs using the temporary access.
What I like about this model is
that the job itself becomes part
of credential lifecycle, right?
We don't have to maintain a permanent
service account key and then build
another process around rotating it.
So we don't want to keep on, as I keep
on saying it from the slide one, right?
We don't want to rotate it, right?
That's a, that's a bit he- big headache
given the scope of environments,
accounts, and all of those, right?
Each organization, so there, there are
some, there are some big organizations
which maintain like 500 accounts or
100 accounts or 50 accounts, right?
Depending upon the team
size and all of those.
So having said that, it's a big
headache for the platform operations.
The pipeline starts,
gets temporary access.
So the flow is the pipeline
starts, gets the temporary access.
Does it work?
Does, does its work like, "Hey, deploy
Lambda, deploy S3 bucket, deploy DynamoDB
table," whatever it is, it deploys it,
and eventually that access expires, right?
And from the application point of view,
this can be almost invisible, right?
So application doesn't matter.
like you spin up an ELB stack and, ELB
stack, and technically, your application
is deployed in the beanstalk and, and
it's deployed, and you have front-facing
and back-facing, and, your security
edition, it's-- happens at the platform.
So technically, your security
edition happens at the platform
and identity layer rather than your
application code to technically
store those credentials, right?
Manage the cloud secrets.
So that's a big relief for the
developers, to move the job, easily.
Now, I wanna talk about little
bit on the, this pattern as well,
like MLOps data ingestion pattern.
the same idea, right?
I have the same, like we
can implement the same idea.
The same idea can be implemented to MLOps.
think about a-- just
simple example, right?
Think about a training job that
needs to read data from another
cloud or another storage environment.
It can be a AWS S3, a GCP,
on-prem cloud, sorry, on-prem data
centers or wherever it is, right?
The traditional approach here is like
you need to put the se- credentials
in the secrets manager, get an ARN,
review that secrets ARN into a training
environment so the job can reach that
data and so that the job can use those
credentials and reach that data, right?
But now we have created another
place where a long-lived credential
can potentially be live, right?
So think about it in that way.
like how can we-- I don't
want to put it as hard-coded,
but we put it as secret ARN.
That's like, ARN is like a value, right?
You, you change the secrets
behind the scenes, but it's
still an hard-coded value, right?
Why do you want to put it in
your training data, right?
You don't want to, technically.
With workload identity, we can instead
of-- we can instead make the access
decision based on the identity of the
particular workload having said that,
and we can make that access specific
to the job, the environment, and where
appropriate, the dataset, appropriate
for the dataset or to resource.
Like technically, you can spin
up a job and an environment, and
what's the goal of that job is to
go there and get the data behind the
scenes, and use that data to your,
operations, with a short-lived token.
So you don't want to use that session
and token, credentials like a secrets
manager ARN and behind the scenes
the values and all of those, right?
You don't want to use that, right?
Why do you want to spend so much time
on that instead of spin up a short-lived
token, get the data, train your data,
you can cache it, and you can reuse it.
So that's, that's, that's
for short period of time.
This is the reference pattern rather than
measure cloud, cross-cloud benchmark.
This is just an example, but
I'm just, putting out there.
I'm not intentionally putting out
the latency numbers because it moves
from cloud to cloud, on this slide
because, the number should be--
actually it should be derived from a
process, with the complete actions.
we run the action and we can
see the flow if we demo it.
but the important point where
what I'm trying to say is
that it can access the model.
here is the access model.
Like how the access model work.
The workload proves its identity instead
of carrying a permanent secret, right?
Instead of carrying a secret ARN, you
can, your workload technically proves
the identity, before, going back, right?
It's just an, overview, like what we do.
coming to the-- this, I want to
spend a little bit time here on this
slide because, now we have achieved
identity over the credentials.
And now we also achieved, authentication,
identity and authentication.
So I will still say that authentication
by itself isn't enough, right?
So sometimes you need to bit more.
Like just because GitHu- GitHub can
issue a token doesn't mean every
GitHub workflow should be trusted
with the same AWS access, right?
So your policy need to be verified,
your claims need to be verified.
So that's the place
where I'm trying to go.
So there is-- this is where the claims
becomes really important, right?
So in the AWS proof, the trust policy
checks the OIDC issuer and the audience,
and it also ties the trusted subject to
the repository and the GitHub environment.
So we are not saying that trust GitHub.
Technically, we are not saying, "Hey,
trust GitHub, like do whatever you
want to do, but, create a session
and AWS does or whatever," right?
So we don't want you to say that.
We are saying trust the
particular identity context when
the claims match, technically.
that gives us much more
precise trust boundary compared
to a wider scale, access.
It is like limiting it to the actions
itself, like scope itself, right?
we can add, yes, of course, we can
add multiple conditions, additional
conditions such as you can refer to a
specific branch, you can refer to a s-
a specific, main, main only talks to
prod, like l- lower environments talk
to a lower, lower account with the
deployment model and everything, right?
It's like somehow you, you
verify it and you process it.
And then there is another control
that is session duration, right?
just think about in this IAM role, right?
you can literally store around, w- that
access control can be a 900 seconds,
technical like 15 minutes, right?
so we're, so we are combining
a claim-level trust with a
short-lived authorization.
So we talked about authentication
and identity in the previous slides.
Now we are talking about
short-lived authorization.
That is the goal we need to achieve.
So having said that, I want to dwell a
little bit deeper into my next chapter,
that is the operation controls, right?
Operation, controls.
Mm, what is operation controls, right?
Operational resiliency
and life cycles, right?
All of-- Life cycle is a primary
thing, life cycle management.
So let's say something got failed, right?
We need to know why it got failed.
How can we-- How do we know it?
so at this point, we have established
identity and authorization, right?
But in the real production environment,
that only part of-- that's, that's
the only part of the story, right?
we also need to know what happened.
What happens when something
fails technically, right?
Then how the trust relationship
is maintained o-over the time.
And, so we have a pattern for that
as well, like that is observability
pattern and, failure handling and
trust cy- trust life cycle management.
So all those patterns,
comes in the next slide.
So I'll talk about a little bit,
more about observability, auditing,
a-and all, all those things, right?
So One thing I always want from a
security architecture is visibility.
You need to know, what happens
if something happens, right?
I want to able to answer it.
If something happens, I want,
technically, my manager will
ask, right, what happened, right?
So I need to answer it.
and I also need to tell
which workload did it.
So which identity was issued, at what
type of identity got issued, and why that
role was assumed, and why that role has
performed that action as well, right?
And which pipeline was responsible
of breaking stuff, which pipeline is
responsible of doing this stuff, which
pipeline was having limited actions.
Like, let's say, simple example, right?
You want to spin up a Lambda where
it needs to talk to a DynamoDB.
Let's say, we are spinning up a
role, but inside the Lambda need--
when the, whenever the Lambda needs
to talk to DynamoDB to get the
data, it was not able to fetch it.
Why?
Because the DynamoDB role and the
claims, the ro- the role of, the
role policy for the DynamoDB was not
established, properly or something
was missing in the policy, right?
You need to know all this
stuff technically, right?
So that can be achieved by
observability and auditing.
at the federation boundary, we can
capture that, capture the identity, claim
context, and platform, platform exposes.
On AWS, we can do a CloudTrail
audit, can give us the audit trail
of role and API activity, what
has happened at the given time.
And we can also correlate the
temporary role session with
the originating pipeline run.
once with the correlation ID matches,
we can also see the what happened in the
CloudTrail, why it got failed, right?
That gives a provision, instead
of just seeing an API call, from
an anonymous-looking credential,
but it gives a relation as well.
And once we have that visibility, we
can start looking into the things, which
doesn't fit the ex- expected pattern,
and unexpected claims, and unusual token
requests, or unexpected access behavior.
Nowadays, observability has
became, observability data
has becomes the major, thing.
Like many AI tools or many ob- AI
observability tools has coming out, right?
many of them use Datadog and
all of those tools, right?
that, that what, that's what makes
identity operational useful, not
just authentication mechanism, right?
So you want to trust it, but you
want to trust it in a right way.
Correct?
So we get anomaly signals, we get
the credential usage tr- traces,
like what happened, short-lived
session- sessions, short-lived token
sessions, and all of those, right?
So yeah, that's, Now I want
to jump into my next slide.
like, as I talked, right?
So something got failure.
Like there is a failure mode, and
there is a resiliency design as well.
So of course, secretless
doesn't mean failureness.
I want to make it as a standard
that, hey, secretless doesn't
mean failureness, right?
There'll still be failures.
Of course, every pipeline will
still have a failures when initial
phase, when it first runs, right?
There are still things that can go wrong.
We can-- we could have latency issues,
latency at the federation or STS boundary.
The identity provider could be
unavailable at the time, right?
So cloud, think about this DR, right?
So region might have dawned
or, something has happened.
A runner might have Kubernetes issues
or clock skew issues or just say,
let's say if your runner is running
in a Docker or Kubernetes, right?
It might have, clock issues, right?
It might be a timed clock or this
might be a dis- a dish issue.
Or we could simply s- have a trust
policy configured incorrectly.
I was talking about in
the previous slide, right?
There might be a possibility, right?
the policy might always not be the same,
like Lambda talking to DynamoDB, right?
So the important design decision
is like what we need to do
when these things happen.
my recommendation here is like for this
architecture is like fail closed, right?
If the federation isn't available, we
shouldn't-- we should not quietly switch
over for long-lived static credential
just to keep the deployment moving.
that would literally get our
security model out of context, right?
Instead of, instead of that, the
failure should be more visible.
The deployment should stop, and the trust
configuration should be fixed before the
next runs, next workflow runs, right?
The secure path should remain.
That is the primary
path we need to follow.
I'm like from my point of view, whenever
there is a issue, right, it, it stopped.
We need to identify why it stopped,
what has happened, and then move on
with, something as fixing the path
prefixes or path, policy definitions
and work from there, right?
It can be a policy configuration.
As, as I said, right, policy
misconfiguration or OIDC claim
scopes can be misaligned.
Sometimes it can be happened.
I'm not saying it cannot be happened,
but there might be happened.
But I would say is like if it
happened, right, it's-- we'll be very
tempted to go back to the traditional
approach, just pass the secrets.
But I would not do that.
I would just wait on, fix on
those, and then move on to the,
approach, like the security model
approach which we are talking about.
Now, I wanna talk about little bit, a bit
more on the trust lifecycle management.
Like trust shouldn't be ignored.
I would treat trust as code technically.
The next piece is like
we, we talk about trust.
Trust is the code.
We need to treat it as code.
So the repository behind the
presentation, so I have, some actions
which has defined in my GitLab page.
But, what does it do is like Terraform
technically, the GitHub has like, the
Terraform established the GitHub page,
and as OIDs provider creates IAM trust
relationship, and it has a trust policy.
It validates the issuer.
you see, if you see the bootstrapping,
right, it validates the issuer, and
it, enforces that, hey, you have
all the claims, all the process,
and all the necessary requirements.
And through that, SGS receives the
temporary credentials for a dedicated
to spin up a private S3 resource, right?
And importantly, this is not long-lived
access key, required by the workflow.
It's just like a temporary flow
where you just need to spin up
an S3 bucket and leave there.
That's it.
Your job is done.
So you need-- you shouldn't be
working anymore there, right?
So you close it.
as I'm not going to do a live code
walkthrough today, but, present,
this, this point of presentation
is just like architecture, right?
Architecture and sec-security model.
But if you want to dig into the
implementation afterward, the repository
is available, and I can share,
like a QR code as well, from here.
You can also use from it.
The-- So I would literally want to
concentrate a little bit more on the
key takeaways, technically what I spoke.
I, I've been speaking like a lot, but
I want to, So I want to just recap
a session, like let, let me bring
little bit everything together here.
So first, workload identity and
OIDC can remove the need for
long-lived cloud credentials in
the federated automation path.
So technically, the second most point
is like the trust decision, right?
So you need to trust it as a, as it yours.
So how you trust your code, right?
You need to make sure the
trust relationship works as
like that as well, right?
So that's the primary thing which you need
to trust it out, and your workload claims.
that is not the just fact that
token, if the token exists,
then only you'll move it.
The third part, right?
Temporary credentials give
us a bounded validity window.
fourth, the system could fail.
We shouldn't add permanent
credentials as a fallback.
That's just because the
federation has a problem, right?
So we need to make sure that,
we are there, like to find the
problems and observability tools.
Use-- There are many
observability tools, right?
So we can easily find out like
what happened behind the scenes.
so ultimately the goal is the
security without adding friction
to the development workflow.
So your security shouldn't be
something neglected, but your
security should be the primary most
concern for your development, right?
So We are ultimately are giving a freedom
to your developer saying that, hey,
you, you should not-- technically you
shouldn't be worried about your access,
like, credentials threats or anything
on that, but you should be worried
about development workflow, right?
So we just want you to work about.
Having said that, the application or
deployment code shouldn't be, should not
have to be managed or underperformed or,
store a permanent credentials, right?
your platform team, right?
Technically DevOps team or platform
team, should establish the identity and
enforce the trust for you technically.
That's what we, do it, and, we
want to give a, like that's, that's
what the platform team do, right?
So technically you define the
scope and, they work for it.
having said that, so to the close,
I'll leave you with a very simple idea.
like the traditional model is
like give workload credential to
ask and protect that credential.
The model we looked today
is little bit different.
establish the identity, validate the
claims, authorizing the workloads,
that comes in the claim-level
trust, short-lived, tokens.
And we talked about observation
patterns and, we also talked
about multiple credentials, right?
So I only want to quote a
little bit from my own words.
That is, don't distribute
the credentials when you can
establish the identity, right?
And, I really thank you,
everyone for staying this long,
and thank you for watching.
And I am Ankit Walawatpati, and
you can see my GitHub page here.
And if you want to, just read,
review the resources, right, you can
just review it, there it as well.
Thank you, and thank you for Confluent
giving me this wonderful opportunity
to talk about, my favorite topic.
Thank you.